《行尸走肉》
我还以为我们得走更远点
I thought we were going further.
是的
We are.
要18英里以外
18 miles out.
那我们为什么停下
So why are we stopping?
我想和你谈谈
I wanted to talk.
拖了一星期 是时候谈谈了
Been waiting a week till we were gonna do this.
- 我就想聊聊 - 不需要
- I just wanna talk. - We don't need to.
需要
We do.
不 兄弟 没必要
No man, we don't.
我明白这情况
We're doing this. I get it.
你们把他带回来的时候他是昏迷的
He was passed out when y'all brought him back,
并不清楚农场的位置
Doesn't know where the farm is.
我不是要说这个
That isn't what I need to talk to you about.
我听说了
I heard.
学校里那事的真相
What really happened at the school.
是为了活下去吗
Was it to survive?
是啊
Yeah.
我们二人必死一个
One of us wasn't gonna make it out.
只能是他
It had to be him.
他腿上的一枪救了卡尔一命
One shot to the leg, Carl lives.
事实上
Reality is…
这里没他什么事
He had no business being here…
去那边也一样
There. Whatever.
你觉得我不会这样做
You don't think I would've done it?
是啊 兄弟 我知道你不会
No, man, I know you wouldn't have.
你觉得我保护不了洛莉和卡尔
You don't think I can keep Lori or Carl safe?
我可没这么说
I didn't say that.
还有我未出生的孩子
Or my baby?
也该由我来保护
Is it gonna have to be me too?
瑞克 只做好人没法生存下去
Rick, you can't just be the good guy and expect to live.Okay?
再也不能了
Not anymore.
我不再是个好人
I'm not the good guy anymore.
为了救卡尔
To save Carl's life,
我会做任何事 任何事
I would've done anything… anything.
洛莉说你很危险
Now Lori says you're dangerous,
但你不是
But you're not gonna be dangerous.
至少对我们 对我 不再是了
Not to us, not to me, not anymore.
看着我
How about you look at me?
你和洛莉
You and Lori…
我知道发生了什么
I get what happened.
当我发现时 其实我很快就发现了
When I figured it out… and I figured it out pretty quickly…
我真想打碎你的下巴
I wanted to break your jaw,
揍得你满地找牙
Let you choke on your teeth.
但我没有
But I didn't.
这不是软弱
That wasn't weakness.
我会付出一切代价
It took everything.
那是我的妻子 我的儿子
That is my wife. That is my son.
我未出生的骨肉
That is my unborn child.
我会为了保护他们而活下去
I will stay alive to keep them alive.
你并不爱她
You don't love her.
你以为你爱 其实不然
You think you do, but you don't.
现在唯一能让我们继续相处的条件
Now the only way you and me keep on…
就是你接受我刚说的一切
Is that you accept everything I just said.
立刻 现在
Right here, right now,
然后我们带着共识继续前进
And we move forward with that understanding.
刚开始的时候只是
When it started it was just…
只是新闻上的几个怪谈
It was a couple of weird stories on the news.
然后 实在是发生得太快
Then… then it was so quick.
噩梦就这么降临了
Everything… it just happened.
两周之后 我在医院里
Two weeks later, I'm in the hospital.
士兵在大厅枪杀普通人
And there were soldiers shooting people in the halls.
他们在杀普通人啊 兄弟 不是行尸
They were shooting people, man, not walkers.
然后行尸涌入
Then the walkers came through.
我想办法把你弄出去
You know, I tried to get you out,
我努力了 但行不通
I tried, but we weren't gonna make it.
兄弟 真是没招
Man, there was no way and I knew it.
但我没法这么活着
But I couldn't live with it.
无法苟且偷生 知道…
I couldn't live, knowing…
但我不得不这样做
But I had to.
不是因为我洛莉和卡尔才活着 兄弟
I didn't keep Lori and Carl alive, man.
他们才是我活着的动力
They kept me alive.
我在这之前我绝没有对她有过念头
I want you to know that I didn't look at her before that.
兄弟 如果有机会重新来过 我会的
Brother, if I could take it all back, I would.
我去检查下绳子
I wanna check the ropes.
没问题
It's all good.
昨天他们回来之后
Rick say anything to you.
瑞克有没有和你说格伦的事
about Glenn when they got back from town?
只说了那时情况很糟
Just that it had gotten pretty bad.
他和以前不一样了
He's not the same.
他说他呆住了
…says he froze.
怪我 说我在他脑海里挥之不去
Blames me. Says I got inside his head.
他回来了 这才是最重要的
He came back… that's what matters.
人总要发泄一下 你懂的
Men have to do certain things… you know that…
用各种莫须有的理由
And they're either gonna blame the little woman.
把责任迁怒在弱女子身上
As the reason they do 'em or the reason they don't.
我和你说
I'll tell you something…
那些在外面发生的事就让它去吧
what happens out there happens out there.
我们
And we…
我们只要努力坚持下去 在他们回来前
We're just trying to keep it together till they get back.
情况挺好的 也许是我
Things were good. Maybe I…
格伦是个大人了
Glenn's a big boy.
他能自作决断 你就
He makes his own choices, and then you…
你有什么要道歉的吗
Do you have anything to apologize for?
告诉他像个男人样振作起来
Tell him to man up and pull himself together.
别用 像个男人 从来没好结果
Just don't say "Man up." it never goes well.
我把这个拿去给贝丝
Let me just get this to beth.
你忙着 我来拿
You go on… I got it.
我们该习惯用刀了
We've gotta start using our knives more.
只有一只行尸的话 用刀更好
If there's one walker, we use our knives.
既安静 又省弹药
We keep things quiet. We save ammunition.
是啊
Yeah.
我们得在冬天前准备点干货
We need dry goods ahead of the winter…
保暖衣物 燃料
Warm clothes… fuel.
也许我们能暂休段时间
Maybe we get a break.
说不定严寒对它们有影响
You gotta think the cold affects them.
就算冻不死 也能减缓它们的速度
If it doesn't kill 'em, it's gotta slow 'em down.
去年一月的第二周
The second week of january last year,
我们那下了很大的雪
We got all that snow and ice.
我表弟困在85号公路上24小时
My cousin got stuck on 85 for 24 hours.
坐在车里 拿着生日蛋糕
sitting in his car with a birthday cake.
准备送给在乔治亚理工学院上学的女朋友
for his girlfriend at Georgia Tech.
他就那么坐着 吃掉了蛋糕
He just sat and ate birthday cake.
听着《指环王》小说的录音带
and listened to the "Lord of the Rings" Book on tape.
要是运气好 等到像去年一样的冬季
We get lucky, we get the same winter as last year.
到了十二月 整个世界就变了
By December, it's a different world.
变安全了
Safer.
也许我们能找到雪地车来逃亡
Maybe we find some snowmobiles to make runs.
听起来不错
That sounds good.
我进来了哦
Knock knock.
要不这样吧
How about this… you, uh…
你先吃完饭
You eat up all your food,
然后我们带你出去走走
We'll get you up and out of here and go take a walk.
这样行吗
What do you say?
出去走走挺好的
It'll do good to be outside.
你怀孕了
You're pregnant.
你怎么能这样
How could you do that?
呃 我也没办法啊
Uh, I don't really have a choice.
你觉得这会改变现状吗
You think it'll make a difference?
当然会
Of course it will.
快吃东西吧
You eat something.
已经过18英里了
It's more than 18.
是啊 我在找个地方
Yeah, I'm looking for a place.
找个地方干嘛
A place for what?
公平对待 给他个机会
Give him a fair shake. A shot.
那儿
There.
（莫特郡 公用工程部）
这地方可以
This'll do.
我们把那孩子扔在这儿 找点补给品
We'll leave the boy here and scavenge some supplies.
那边
Over there.
等等
Wait.
像我说的
Like I said.
用枪简单快捷
Gun's quick, easy,
但还有别的办法
but other ways to do this.
还有一只 该你了
One more. Your turn.
嘿 瑞克
Hey, rick.
我没发现有咬痕
I don't see any bites.
那肯定是抓伤
Gotta be scratches then…
这人的手上 那人的脸部
This one's hand, other one's cheek.
这儿有行尸 山下有烧过的尸体
They had walkers here… burned bodies down the hill.
我猜肯定是抓伤了
I guess it gotta be scratches then, huh?
吃不下东西吗
Couldn't eat a thing, huh?
你得…
You're gonna…
我知道这很艰难
I know how hard it is.
我曾经想联系我妈 打了好几天
I tried for days to reach my mom,
想让她接电话
and get her on the phone.
- 我只能想… - 这太没意义了
- I can only assume… - It's just so pointless.
你还有玛姬
You have Maggie,
你爸爸 帕特里夏 还有吉米
And your father, Patricia and Jimmy.
为了他们 你要保持坚强
And you've gotta stay strong for them.
我希望自己能说「最后都会好起来」
I wish I could promise you it would be all right in the end.
但我不能
I can't,
但我们能让现在的情况好起来
But we can make now all right…
我们必须这样
And we have to.
谢谢
Thank you.
我就回来 然后去走走
I'll be right back. We'll go take that walk.
贝丝
Beth?
亲爱的 把刀给我
You give it to me, sweetheart.
你不能这么做
You don't wanna do this.
安德莉亚 你有看见玛姬和赫谢尔吗
Andrea, have you seen Maggie or Hershel?
我没看见赫谢尔 但我见到玛姬和格伦路过
I haven't seen Hershel, but I saw Maggie and Glenn walk by.
- 大概二十分钟前吧 - 能帮我找找她吗
- maybe 20 minutes ago. - Could you find her for me?
我得回屋子里去
I've gotta get back to the house.
当然
Of course.
这是搞什么
What the hell is this?
拜托 别干傻事
Oh, come on, don't be stupid.
我欠你们的
I owe you guys.
我能帮助你们的
I can help protect what you've got.
要是你们把我扔在这儿 当初何必救我
Why would you save my life just to kill me by leaving me here?
一个人 一个人无法生存
One guy… one guy can't make it alone.
所以我才和他们一起 我原本孤独一人
That's why I was with those dudes… I was alone.
别干傻事 我和他们不同
Don't be stupid! I'm not like them!
我只是个普通人
I'm just some guy!
我也看足球赛
I used to watch football.
也上网到处逛
and screw around on the internet.
我和我妈一起住
I lived with my mom!
我也像你们一样失去亲人
I lost her like you lost people.
我和玛姬一起上学 老天爷啊
I went to school with Maggie for god's sake!
我上教堂做礼拜
I went to church.
我是大学棒球队的替补队员
I rode the bench on varsity baseball.
你和玛姬一起上学吗
You went to school with Maggie?
回答我
Answer the question!
你是不是和玛姬一起上学
Did you go to school with maggie?
我呃 她不认得我
I… it… she didn't know me.
甚至不知道我的存在
Didn't even know I existed.
我知道她这个人
I mean, I knew her.
我知道她爸爸
I knew who her dad was.
我绝不会做出任何事
There is no way I would ever do anything.
- 去伤害她和她家人 - 老天啊
- to hurt her or her family. - Jesus.
也不会伤害你们
Or you… or your people!
我跟那帮人不同
I'm not like the guys I was with!
瑞克 他知道农场在哪儿
He knows where the farm is, Rick.
他知道我们在哪儿
Where we are… he knows.
如果他回到了他朋友身边
Say he finds his way back to his people…
肖恩 不行
Shane, no!
现在不行 不行
Not now… just not now!
那何时可以 瑞克 何时
Well, when, Rick? When?
等我有机会好好考虑时
When I've had a chance to think about it.
别让他杀我 求求你
Don't let him kill me. Please don't.
闭嘴
Shut up!
我们要回去 这是条人命
We're going back. It's a man's life.
我需要好好想一晚上
I need a night to think it through.
你打算带这王八羔子回去
You're gonna bring this piece of garbage…
这王八羔子
This piece of garbage who…
他冲你开过枪
He shot at you, Rick.
他和他兄弟想杀了你
He ran with men who tried to kill you.
带这种人回去 洛莉能睡个安稳觉吗
You gonna bring him back to where Lori sleeps?
卡尔能睡吗
To where carl sleeps?
我们会把他锁在谷仓里
He'll be locked up in the barn,
- 除非你打开谷仓 - 别扯着事儿
- unless you bust it open. - Oh, don't start that shit.
- 我要思考一晚 - 兄弟 你思考
- I'm taking the night. - Man, you take that…
你考虑半天 思来想去
You think on it, rick. Keep struggling with it.
这没什么难的
It ain't hard, man.
正确的选择就是能让我们活下去的
The right choice is the one that keeps us alive.
你从来都是这样
It's always the same with you.
从一开始就是这样
It's like the first moment…
你办事从来都是这样
it's whenever you're put to the test.
别假装你知道前面的路
Stop acting like you know the way ahead,
就像你知道规则一样
like you know the rules.
没有规则 兄弟 我们迷失了
There are no rules, man. We're lost.
不 不 兄弟 我知道我在哪
No-no-no, man. I know exactly where I am.
你什么都不知道
You don't know shit anymore.
你不能这么干 瑞克
I don't think you can do it, Rick.
这事我说了算 伙计
It's my call, man.
我不觉得你能保他们安全
I don't think you can keep them safe.
靠
Damn!
天啊
God!
别
No!
放开我 伙计
Get off me, man.
你不能这么干
You're not doing this!
这些事不再由你决定了
You don't get to make these calls anymore.
我不会让你这么干的
I won't let you.
你疯了吗 爸爸发现怎么办
Are you crazy? What if dad finds out?
他会怎么做 为了自杀而杀了我
What's he gonna do? Kill me for committing suicide?
别幼稚
Stop being such a brat.
他会死的
He'd die.
我也会的
So would I.
不只是你
This isn't just about you.
我们都没有妈妈
We all lost mom.
我不能忍的是我们会失去彼此
We'll lose each other and I couldn't stand that.
所以你要放弃吗
So you give up?
来吧 贱人 看看你有什么能耐
Come on, bitch. Let's see what you got.
赫谢尔在哪
Where's Hershel?
他不想知道
He doesn't want to find out yet.
这是家务事 让他们自己解决
It's a family affair. We'll let them work it out.
就是那么解决的吗
That's working it out?
等贝丝不闹了的时候
When Beth stops fighting,
才是该担心的时候
that's when it's time to worry.
你太自私了
You are being so selfish!
这本可以更好的解决
This could've been handled better.
怎么解决
How so?
你不该拿走刀子
You shouldn't have taken the knife away.
- 你说什么 - 你错了
- Excuse me? - You were wrong,
就像戴尔拿走我的枪 那不由你们管
like dale taking my gun. That wasn't your decision.
她必须学着靠自己生活
She has to choose to live on her own.
她必须找到活下去的理由
She has to find her own reasons.
要我绑住她吗
Want me to tie a noose for her?
如果她是认真的 她会找到办法
If she's serious, she'll figure out a way.
这不意味着我不能阻止她
Doesn't mean I can't stop her.
或让她知道我在意
or let her know that I care.
那没用 洛莉
That has nothing to do with it, Lori.
她面临太多选择
She only has so many choices in front of her,
她觉得最好的就是自杀
and she believes the best one is suicide.
- 那不是个选择 - 它当然是
- That's not an option. - Of course it is.
她不必被呼来喝去或者被像孩子一样对待
She doesn't need to be yelled at or treated like a child.
她需要一把上膛的枪对吗
She needs a loaded gun, right?
如果我不让你进去你会理解吧
You'll understand if I don't send you in there.
我熬过来了
I came through it.
还成了一个对队里多么有用的人啊
And became such a productive member of the group.
让玛姬以自己的方式解决吧
Let Maggie handle this her way.
我做了贡献
I contribute.
帮忙保证这里的安全
I help keep this place safe.
男人们可以自己解决
The men can handle this on their own.
不需要你帮忙
They don't need your help.
抱歉 那你想让我做什么
I'm sorry. What would you have me do?
有很多事要做呢
Oh, there's plenty of work to go around.
你说真的吗
Are you serious?
都天下大乱了
Everything falls apart,
你却指责我不洗衣服
You're in my face over skipping laundry?
加重其他人的负担
Puts a burden on the rest of us,
让我卡萝尔 帕特里夏和玛姬
On me and Carol, and Patricia and Maggie.
做饭 打扫和照顾贝丝
Cooking, cleaning and caring for Beth.
你 你不关心任何人
And you… you don't care about anyone.
除了你自己 你坐在房车上
But yourself… you sit up on that R.V.,
揣着猎枪晒太阳
Working on your tan with a shotgun in your lap.
不 我在监视行尸
No, I am on watch against walkers.
那才是重要的
That is what matters,
而不是关注柠檬水里有没有新鲜的薄荷
Not fresh mint leaves in the lemonade.
我们在维持稳定
And we are providing stability.
努力创造有意义的生活
We are trying to create a life worth living.
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
我跟着瑞克 干掉两个行尸
Look, I went after Rick. I took down two walkers.
玛姬的车撞毁之后
After crashing Maggie's car.
别说的好像只有你才能保护自己
Don't act like you're the only one who can take care of herself.
你为此道歉过吗
Ever apologize for that?
撞毁她的
Crashing her…
- 你疯了 - 不 你才是
- You're insane. - No, you are.
你才是那个自我为中心的
And you're the one that's self-centered,
觉得一切都是理所应当
the way you take it all for granted.
我丈夫在外面
My husband is out there.
几百次
for the hundredth time.
我儿子遭到枪击
My son was shot.
你还敢说我觉得是理所应当的吗
Don't you dare tell me I take this for granted.
你还没懂 对吗
You don't get it, do you?
你丈夫死而复生
Your husband came back from the dead,
你儿子也是 现在你又有了个孩子
Your son too. And now you've got a baby on the way.
我们其他人失去的数不胜数
The rest of us have piled up our losses…
我 卡萝尔 贝丝
Me, Carol, Beth.
但你却越得越多
but you just keep on keeping on.
- 我们都经历了苦难 - 玩过家家
- We have all suffered. - Playing house,
像个女王蜂
acting like the queen bee,
为所有人定规矩除了你自己
laying down rules for everybody but yourself.
你知道吗 继续啊
You know what? Go ahead.
进去然后告诉那小女孩
Go in there and tell that little girl.
一切都会好的
that everything's gonna be okay,
就像你一样
just like it is for you.
她会有老公 儿子 宝宝 男友
She'll get a husband, a son, baby, boyfriend.
只要她保持乐观
She just has to look on the bright side.
妈妈会觉得丢脸的
Mom would be ashamed.
当她知道她养了这么个胆小鬼
To learn she raised such a coward.
- 爸爸怎么办 贝丝 - 他自己都毫无头绪
- What about dad, Beth? - He's clueless.
- 他让我们等待解药 - 他知道他错了
- He had us waiting for a cure. - He knows he was wrong.
爸爸什么时候承认过错误
When has dad ever admitted he was wrong?
他只是告诉瑞克的人他们想听的
He's just telling Rick's group what they want to hear.
吉米呢
And Jimmy?
我们约会了三个月 现在我就该嫁给他了
We went out for three months and now I'm married to him?
我呢
And me?
你能那么对我吗
You could do that to me?
我不愿再参加一个葬礼
I can't take another funeral.
你逃不掉的
You can't avoid it.
我们还等什么
What are we waiting for?
- 我们应该一起 - 什么
- We should both do it. - What?
同时 互相帮助
At the same time. Help each other.
- 不 - 太难了
- No. - It's hard to do it.
- 没人想干但是 - 别 求你了
- No one wants to but… - No, please don't.
我们做了就会安宁了 很容易
We can do it so it's peaceful, easy.
别说了
Stop talking like that.
我们选的 然后就会结束了
Our choice, and then it would be over.
否则当农场沦陷
Or we'll be forced to do.
我们就被咬死了
it when the farm and this house is overrun.
- 没人能保护我们 - 不会的
- No one can protect us. - That's not true.
谁 格伦吗
Who, Glenn?
我听说发生了什么
I heard what happened.
瑞克只会救他的家人
Rick will save his family,
其他人也一样
the others too.
我们是孤独的
We're alone.
你 我 帕特里夏
You, me, Patricia,
只有爸爸和吉米
with only dad and Jimmy.
对抗整个世界的行尸
against a whole world of those things.
我不想被吃掉
I don't wanna be gutted.
我想死
I wanna go…
在这张床上 今晚…
in this bed, tonight…
你陪在我身边
with you beside me.
求你了
Please.
好吧
Okay.
你们想要血吗
You want some of that?
卧槽
Oh shit.
你不能一直盯着她
You can't sit on top of her.
我不能留她一个人待着
I can't leave her by herself.
你必须那样
You're gonna have to.
你太累了
You're exhausted.
去透透气 我陪着她
Go get some air. I'll sit with her.
去吧
Go ahead.
洗漱一下 吃点东西
Wash up, get something to eat.
- 我看着 - 好的
- I got it. - Okay.
好的
Okay.
- 谢谢 - 没事
- Thanks. - Okay.
你不准备说点什么
Aren't you gonna say something?
这就是你想要的吗
Is this what you want?
痛苦不会自己离开
The pain doesn't go away.
你必须学着承受
You just make room for it.
噢 见鬼
Oh! Holy shit.
你他妈往哪儿跑
Where the hell do you think you're going?
是个人都会跑
What did you expect me to do?
求你了 放我走吧
Please, just let me go, man.
你本来就是来放我的
That's what you came here for.
我不会给别人泄密的
I'm not gonna tell anyone anything.
闭嘴
Shut up.
你要留在这里
You wanna stay here?
救那个刚才想砸扁你头的家伙
Help the guy that just tried to bash your head in?
那里有10个行尸
There's 10 roamers there.
你觉得你能干掉他们吗
You think you can take them on?
它们没看到我们 我们能逃走
They don't see us. We can get out of here.
好吧
Fine!
那你给我一把枪
But let me have a gun.
我帮你
I'll help you.
我能向你证明
I'll show you.
- 怎么了 - 我们走
- What? - Let's go.
- 什么 - 这是他的错
- What? - He did this.
- 我们走 - 谢谢你 谢谢你
- We're going. - Oh, thank you. Thank you.
瑞克 别这样
Rick… no, man.
回来啊兄弟
Come back, man.
贝丝
Beth?
贝丝 贝丝
Beth? Beth?
玛姬
Maggie?
她在里面 我听见玻璃的声音
She's in there. I heard glass.
贝丝 你没事吧
Beth, you all right?
别那样做贝丝 别那样做
Don't do this, Beth. Don't do this.
开门 求你了
Open up, please.
上帝啊 我让安德莉亚看着她
God, I left her with andrea.
钥匙呢
Where's the key?
我不知道
I don't know.
贝丝宝贝 求你了开门
Beth honey, please open the door.
我没生气
I'm not mad.
我没生你气 贝丝
I'm not mad, Beth.
玛姬
Maggie.
等等
Hang on.
对不起
I'm sorry.
没事了
That's okay.
原地等着
Stay there.
你觉得爽吗
Yeah, you like that?
肖恩
Shane!
快跑
Run!
往后门跑
Go for the back door!
快
Come on!
快进来
Come on, get in!
走 快走
Go, man, go! Come on!
你看到了吗 看我们多厉害啊
You see that? You see what we did?
好好开车
Just keep driving.
你去哪里了
Where were you?
我听说了 她还好吗
I heard. Is she all right?
如果你看着她就不会发生这事
She would be if you had stayed with her.
你去哪了
Where were you?
- 她伤的重吗 - 割口不深
- How bad is she? - It wasn't deep.
她想活下去 她做了选择
She wants to live. She made her decision.
- 她试着自杀 - 不 她没有
- She tried to kill herself. - No, she didn't.
我父亲正在缝合她手腕
My father is stitching her wrist right now.
她会活下去的
She'll live.
离她远点
Stay away from her.
离我们俩远点
From both of us.
你不准再踏入这房子半步
Don't you dare step foot inside this house again.
我不会说她是对的
I'm not gonna say she was right,
但贝丝做了自己的选择
but Beth has made her choice.
她想活下去 她现在自己也明白
She wants to live and now she knows it.
有时你必须用超常规手段
And sometimes you have to cross the line.
如果你想杀我
If you wanna kill me,
光用扳手可不够
you're gonna have to do better than a wrench.
我很可能会杀了那小子
Probably gonna have to kill that boy,
但晚上我会好好考虑
but I am gonna think about it at night.
杀人不应该那么简单
It can't be that easy, killing someone,
不管杀谁
killing anyone.
你懂的
You know that.
那是我的妻子
That is my wife.
那是我的儿子
That is my son.
那是我的孩子
That is my child.
如果你还想跟我们一起
If you're gonna be with us,
你就必须服从我的领导 信任我
you gotta follow my lead, you gotta trust me.
你应该回归了
It's time for you to come back.